けどよ　こんな俺のこと こんなタコな俺のこと カッコいいって 言ってくれた奴を
Fearsome monsters... Exotic creatures...
「友達になれる」って 言ってくれた奴を
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
見殺しになんか　できるかよ!!
Evil enclaves... Unexplored lands...
絶対に助けるからな！
The word "unknown" holds magic.
死ぬんじゃねえぞ!!
And some incredible people are
drawn to that magic.
ん？ せっかく 透明になれる能力があるのに
Letter x From x Gon
においが体に染みついて すぐにバレちゃうよ。 ヘヘっ　忠告ありがとうよ。
"Mito-san and Grandma,
how are you doing?
だが　正味　問題ねえ。
I'm doing fine.
透明能力は 名刺みたいなもんでな 本当の力は　ワンランク上だぜ？
I just passed the Hunter
Exam's Third Phase.
んっ？
Isn't that great?
まぁ　見てな。
But it's been a tough ride.
えっ!? 消えた！　一瞬で 気配も完全にない たばこも残り香だけだ いない 透明になっただけじゃ　ない
First, after leaving the island, But that's where I met
Leorio and Kurapika."
あんな一瞬で 全く葉音も立てずに
You can't buy class with money, Leorio.
絶対に無理だ！ 一体　どうやって？
That's three times now. Step outside.
うわ！ 一体　どこから？
I'll end the filthy Kurta bloodline,
here and now.
んっ？　俺は ずっと　ここにいたぜ。
Take that back, Leorio!
第２の能力 「パーフェクトプラン」。
Take that back! That's Leorio-san to you.
お前さん　さっき俺に ちゃんと触ってたぜ？ けど　触ってるってことを 意識できなかった。
Take back what you said!
えっ？　触ってた？
Take back your words,
and I'll forgive you, Leorio.
影の薄い奴っているだろ？
How many times must I repeat myself? You should show me some respect.
団体でファミレスとかに行って
I won't back down.
いつもウエートレスに 水　もらえないような奴。
Then I have no choice...
さっきの 透明になる能力なんてな
Damn it!
お前さんだけだ。
Thanks, Gon!
そんな大事なことを　俺に？
You saved my life.
まっ　信頼を深めるためさ。
I couldn't have done it alone.
言い寄ったほうが まず　リスクを負わなきゃな。
These two helped save you. Huh?
信用してもらえなきゃ 本題に入れねえからよ。
Thank you very much! No, you don't need to thank me.
本題って さっきのパートナーって話？
Well...
ああ　だが　今は　その話は　いい。 んっ？ 言ったろ？　信頼関係が先さ。
Yeah, I'm glad you're okay. Yeah! So I'll be returning to my station!
その話は　お前さんから 「パートナーになってもいい」って 言葉を聞いてからだ。
What? I apologize for my rude behavior.
うん！　なってもいいよ。 早!!
Sorry, Leorio-san.
駆け引きしがいのねえ ガキだな　おい！
Wh-What's with the sudden change?
疑え！　もっと疑えよ　俺を！ 世の中をよ！
We sound like strangers...
その上で　紆余曲折　経て信じろ！
Just call me Leorio... Leorio works.
え　いいって言ってんのに 面倒くさいなぁ。
I'm also sorry.
大体　お前さん１人で 勝手に決めていいのかよ!?
I take back everything I said.
仲間がいるんだろう？ そいつと　もめるぞ！
I was wrong.
俺みてぇな怪しげな化け物と 相談なく組んだらよ！
"This led to the three of us traveling to
うわ　…って俺 何で自分をおとしめてんだろ
the Hunter Exam site together.
クソ　俺だって　好きで こんな姿になったんじゃねえ！ 忙しい人だなぁ
But the journey wasn't so simple."
２０年来の仲間に 裏切られることだってあるしな。 信頼なんてな　時間じゃねえ
Exciting two-choice quiz!
セイ　ホ！
Here is your question...
ノリ　悪ぃな　ダチにゃなれねえ。
Your son and daughter have
been kidnapped.
こっちのセリフだなぁ
You can only rescue one.
で　大丈夫なのかよ。 何が？
Select 1 for your son,
or 2 for your daughter.
俺と組む話だよ 仲間は反対しねえのか？
Which will you rescue?
ん　多分　大反対。
She's making fun of us...
あっ　でも　俺が 絶対　譲らなきゃ大丈夫。
Don't stop me, Kurapika!
結局　キルアが　渋々折れるから。
I won't be satisfied until I've
taught this hag a lesson!
そうか　そいつも苦労してんな。
Calm down, Leorio! How am I supposed to calm down?
まぁ　いいや 大丈夫だって言うなら信用する。
You'll waste our correct response!
んじゃ　本題に入ろう。 ん。
Correct response? We gave the right answer.
王を倒す!!
Silence was the correct response.
理由が知りたいか？
Please... Please save my wife...
うん　そりゃ　もちろん。 言うのを待ってたんだけど
Leorio, we'll leave the
injured man to you!
どんな恨みかまでは さすがに今は言えねえな。
Kurapika!
…って 言ってほしいんだろうなぁ チッ…　そんなに聞きたいんじゃ しょうがねえな。
Who are you?
今　言うの!? なんて　ウソだよ！ いくら頼まれても今は言えねえよ。
How can you tell that I'm
not the same one? Huh?
頼んでないよ。
Your face is completely different.
フ。
And your voice is a little
higher and thinner.
ペギーって名前だ。
What? Did I say something funny?
俺の目の前で 頭を吹っ飛ばされてな。
Your superhuman physical ability
and powers of observation
だが　俺は恩人が殺されたことに 全く気づけなかった。
make you worthy to take the Hunter Exam.
えっ？　何で？ 目の前で見てたんでしょ？
You pass.
忘れてたのさ　殺されたペギーが 俺の里親だったってことをな。
"Finally, the Hunter Exam began!"
俺が人間だった頃の記憶。
The entry period for
Hunter applicants has ended.
全てを思い出したわけじゃねえ。
The Hunter Exam will now begin!
親の名前　自分の名前 生い立ちの断片。
You must follow me to Phase Two.
王に殺された キメラアントの幹部　ペギー。
This is the exam's First Phase.
ペギーは　人間だった頃の 義父の名前でもある。
"That's when I made friends
教育熱心でな いつも分厚い本を抱えてて…。
with a boy around my age,
named Killua." Hey, how old are you? I'm twelve years old.
生前も　後生大事に ＮＧＬの教本を抱えてたよ。
We're the same age. Huh? Guess I'll run, too.
みんな　人間の記憶があるんだね。
Wow! That was cool!
明らかに獣の特性のほうが 強い奴もいるし 何考えてるか 分からねえ奴もいる。
I'm Gon. Hey, why do you want to
become a Hunter? Me?
でも　ようやく少し分かった。 んっ？
I'm not really interested in
becoming a Hunter. Huh?
何で　メレオロンのこと 会ってすぐに 信用する気になれたのか。
I heard the exam was supposed
to be really hard, so I thought it'd be fun.
すごく　人間くさいんだ。
But this is disappointing.
今まで会った キメラアントの誰よりも。
What about you?
…って言うか メレオロンは人間だよ　もう。
Well, my dad's a Hunter.
そうかい？ 俺が　お前さんから受けた印象は 真逆だぜ。 えっ？
So I want to become a Hunter,
like my dad. Hmm... What kind of Hunter is he?
俺は　お前さんに 人間離れした怪物性を感じた。
I don't know.
だから　組む気になったんだぜ？ 境なんて あってないようなものさ。
That's kinda weird. Really? You want to be like your dad, but you don't know anything about him?
さて　ようやく本題だ。
I was raised by Mito-san, so I've only seen my dad in pictures.
が　その前に…
Who's Mito-san?
そろそろ名前を教えてくれよ？
Aunt Mito. Oh...
俺はゴン　ゴン＝フリークス！
When he was twelve,
my dad took the Hunter Exam. He passed and became a Hunter.
俺には　もう１つの能力がある。
Then he left the island.
今　その発動条件を満たした。
I want to find out why he
chose to be a Hunter
えっ？
over being with me.
見せてやろう　第３の能力。
The exit! Whew...
発動!!
Goal!
フン。
Yay! I win! What are you talking about? I was faster...
これって 俺にも「パーフェクトプラン」が 使えたってっこと？
It's mine!
分かったようだな この能力のすごさが。 この能力を使えば
I commend you on your efforts. "Thanks to Killua, the Hunter Exam's been a lot of fun.
敵に全く気づかれずに近づき
We're best friends now."
いくら　王が強かろうが 隙だらけの急所に 最強の一撃をぶち込めば倒せる！
Hunter Vocabulary
ヘイ　ゴン。
Letter
お前こそ　俺が求めていた相棒。 クソったれの王に 前代未聞の必殺技を 食らわすナイスガイさ！
"Applicants come from around the world
to take the Hunter Exam, so there are lots of amazing people."
見てたぜ　ゴン。 お前さんの「ジャン！　ケン！ グ!!」ってやつ。
Not bad, little boy.
フ　相手は俺の部下だ。
Is that a fishing pole?
お前さんの実力を知るために 部下をけしかけたんだが
What a fascinating weapon. Allow me a closer look.
奴らのほうが…。
Your fight is with
あっ　あ　気にしなくていいぜ。 俺の目を盗んで 快楽で殺生してるような連中だ。
me!
まっ　奴らからしたら 変わっちまったのは 俺のほうなんだろうけどよ。
You came to rescue your friend?
パートナーの話なんだけど
Such a good boy.
俺より適任者がいる。
And that expression...
待った。
Very nice.
お前さんは信頼している っていうか たとえ　この先 信頼を裏切られても
I'm getting excited now...
俺がそのまんま 信頼できるかどうかは　別！ 分かってもらえるか？
How wonderful...
うん 言いたいことは分かるけど…。 俺にとっては 命が懸かってるんだぜ？
I really do love that look.
「パーフェクトプラン」は 決して無敵の能力じゃ　ない。 むしろ　ひどく　もろい。
Do not fear.
俺を意識できないってことはだ
I will not kill your friend.
言い換えれば　意識できないだけで そこに　俺は存在する。
He passed.
つまり　敵の攻撃は ちゃんと俺に当たるんだよ。 そういう能力を持った奴が
Yes, you pass, as well.
近づいて来てるかもしれないと 思ったら　どうする？
Grow up and become a fine Hunter.
たとえ　まぐれでも　その攻撃に 当たっちまったら　アウトなんだ。
But I was pretty excited, as well.
自慢じゃねえが　俺の戦闘能力は キメラの中じゃ　下の下。
I was so scared, I wanted to run away. But I couldn't.
雑務兵クラスだ。
And at the same time, I was excited.
王どころか　師団長クラスの パンチでも　一撃も持たねえよ。
Isn't that strange?
透明になるだけなら 「円」を使えば感知できる。
"At the start of the Hunter Exam,
there were 404 applicants.
これは　実証済みだし 他の師団長も知ってること。 俺の能力は　その程度だと 思わせておく必要がある。
But by the time we reached
the Third Phase, only 41 were left." Ahem...
「『円』さえ使えば大丈夫だ」とな。 誰も俺の能力を 知らないからこそ
Everyone, the exam's Third Phase
will begin here, at the top of Trick Tower.
この能力は　無敵でいられるんだ。
Trick Tower?
前置きが長くなったな。
To pass this phase, you must reach the tower's base alive.
つまり　これ以上　俺の能力を 知る者は増やしたくない。 たとえ　ゴンが 絶対の信頼を置いてる奴でもな。
The time limit is seventy-two hours.
確かめてみれば　いいよ。
Wh-What is this place?
はっ？
Look over there.
[TEL] 離れた場所から見ててよ。
Allow me to explain, gentlemen.
もしも…。 [TEL]　よぉ！ 待ってたぜ　こら！ やってくれたな！ 今　どこだ？
Before you are some of
Trick Tower's prisoners.
聞きてぇことが山ほどあんぞ。
The Hunter Exam Committee
おめぇらのおかげで ボスが動いたぜ。
has also officially hired them
as examiners.
計画は　大幅に狂ったが 俺は　おめぇらを支持する。
You will be fighting against
the five of them. There's too much at stake
without knowing
[TEL]　やっぱり５００万人を 見殺しには　できねえってよ。
what they have up their sleeves. Given that, I shall... No, I'll go!
ボスの能力で首都を 包囲したそうだ。
Tonpa-san?
能力を分散してる余裕は なくなるはずだ。 つまり
Let the fight begin!
[TEL]　うんうん。
I...
[TEL]　だが　ボスとノヴさんは この先　ネフェルピトーの足止めに
I give! Huh?
全精力を使うことになる。
What?
結果　作戦決行の際 護衛軍の１匹と戦う力は もう残らないだろうと言ってる。
Did he just give up?
[TEL] もちろん国民大会に向けて
M-Maybe he meant "Give me a sec"?
大虐殺の危険は　依然　高いままだ。 状況は　何ひとつ良くなってねえ。
We each light a candle
at the same time. The one whose candle goes
out first is the loser.
[TEL]　会長との連絡は もう　不可能だそうだ。 決行日時のギリギリまで どこかで集中して
Hey! Look at Gon's candle!
牙を磨いてるから。
The flame suddenly became stronger!
俺達４人で判断するんだ。
He must have hidden gunpowder or some other
highly flammable substance inside, to make the candle burn faster!
新たに援軍を呼ぶか 俺達だけで　護衛軍３匹とやるか。
If the fire is stronger, then a little breeze won't extinguish it.
キルアの意見を聞きたいな。
He's fast!
なるほど あいつが１人でやってたのか。
I win!
ダメだ　つながんない 切ってるみたい。
A tattoo of a spider with twelve legs...
[TEL]　そうか… まぁ　まめにかけてみてくれ。
That's...
とにかく　一度会おうぜ
I'm Majitani, one of the
Phantom Troupe's four kings!
早いほうがいい。 [TEL]　うん。
Consider that first strike
my way of saying hello.
じゃあ　互いの現在地を結んだ 中間地点にするか。
This is your last chance to surrender.
ここだな　マンダイ市。
I'm still willing to...
うん　分かった。
Huh?
王手。
Wh-What?
ひぃ！ 二度　言わすな。
Right! In that case, we'll use
rock-paper-scissors!
２２手前で　勝負はすでに 決しておったはずだろうが。
A bet on who'll win a game
of rock-paper-scissors!
なぜ　そこで投了しなかった。
What?
余が　手を誤るとでも思ったか？
It's so obvious what you'll use.
あっ…。 うぅ…。
I can read minds.
ぐっ…。
Your bluffing won't scare me!
あ！　あっ　あっ…。
You'll believe me soon enough.
あ！
Let's do this!
たわけが。
Rock... Paper...
ルールブックを。
Well? What will you use next?
シンプルに見えて 実は非常に複雑です。
Think hard. Come on.
将棋より 時間がかかるかもしれません。
Damn! Man, I have no idea what to think!
頼む　帰らせてくれ おまえら　一体…
I win!
誰か！　助けてくれ！
How are we settling this contest?
うわっ。
Contest? I believe you're confused.
あっ…　メガネ。 お静かに。
This will be a one-sided massacre.
王の御前です。 あっ。
I have no interest in the exam
or any offer of amnesty.
あ！　あぁ…。
I just want to hear you scream. Really? Okay.
どちらか選べ。
Then the loser is the one who dies.
今すぐ　余の前に座るか
Yeah, that's right.
死ぬかだ。
I'll tear your body apart.
それで　ベストに戻せ。
That's...
連敗の言い訳を聞くほど 気は長くない。
mine.
死ぬ気で休め。
G-Give it back.
まさか将棋の半分以下の時間で 攻略するとは…。 コツをつかんだだけのことだ。
Please select a path.
チェス　囲碁　将棋
There are two choices. One path allows five to pass, but is long and difficult.
ルールは違えど 一級の打ち手には その打ち筋に独特の呼吸がある。
The other path allows only three, but is short and easy.
故に 相手の呼吸を乱すことが肝要。
I'm going to press O.
定石を知ると 相手の呼吸が見えて来る。
We made it all the way here together. I want us all to pass together.
そこからは　相手が 呼吸しにくい手を生み出すだけだ。 全ての勝負に通じる真理かと。
Gon... Even if it's a big risk, I want to give it a shot!
退屈させるだけかと思われますが。 うむ　あと何が残っている？
We entered the long and difficult path.
この国でプロ化されているのは あと１つ
Then cut a hole in the wall, to sneak into the short and easy path.
東ゴルトーは発祥国でもあり 国民のほぼ全員が打てるそうです。
My butt hurts... I didn't expect a slide
ルールブックをよこせ。
for the short and easy path.
王を詰むのは チェスや将棋と同じですが
Three of them... Thirty seconds remain. That was really close.
駒を３枚まで重ねることができ
My hands are covered with blisters.
開始時の駒配置も 自軍陣地内ならば自由です。 立体的な視点が必要となり
Same here. Leorio, applicant #403,
is the twenty-third to pass.
他の遊戯とは やや趣が異なるかもしれません。
My hands are blistered, but all five of us cleared
the tower together.
１５年ほど前から 世界大会が行われていますが
All thanks to Gon!
東ゴルトー代表は いまだ無敗です。
The Third Phase of the exam is over.
現世界王者は３代目で 大会５連覇中。
Twenty-five applicants have passed.
そいつに勝てば 余が世界一ということか。
One has died.
余戯の締めくくりに　ふさわしい。 呼べ。
"And so, I've completed the exam's
Third Phase, Mito-san.
選別まで残り　６日 この日　招き入れた この少女が
Ging, your son is following
後に自分の運命に 大きく　かかわることを
in your footsteps.
王は知らない
Well? Are you happy?